In my last video I got a lot of comments like this where people are saying, well what happened
to the Jews that lived in the Arab world, why aren't they living there right now?
And it's a little bit difficult to explain because every Arab country kind of has its
own story, it's difficult to summarize it all into one video, but I'll try my best.
The contention that's being made is that the Jews who lived in the Arab world were
expelled because of anti-Jewish bias and bigotry.
There's no doubt that for over a thousand years Jews lived amongst the Muslims in the
Arab world and in the Muslim world in relative peace, this is a historical fact.
And it wasn't until the beginning of the Zionist project that the spectre of dual loyalties
was raised.
So Arab populations started to look at the Jewish population as though, are you loyal to us
or are you loyal to the Zionist project?
And they weren't crazy for thinking this because the Jewish militias, even before the
state of Israel, literally had a group in their militia called the Arab section.
And that was Arab Jews who were utilized for the sake of espionage.
They would spy on the Palestinians and on the Arab countries abroad.
In fact, go to Netflix.
There's a show called The Spy by Sacha Baron Cohen, where he is, um, it's a true story
based on an Egyptian Jew who goes undercover in Syria and provides intelligence to Israel.
So they weren't crazy to have this idea about dual loyalties.
Now you might say, but it's bigoted for you to say, well, because there's this group who
are probably a small minority who are engaged in espionage for the Zionist project, for you
to accuse the entire Jewish community in the Arab countries as having dual loyalties.
And to this, I agree.
Christianity is part of the conversation, but it's not the entire conversation.
Another element of it that's really important is the fact that Zionism is a settler project.
And a settler project requires, requires settlers.
And so when they realized they reached their limit of European Jews who were going to go
to the state of Israel, they realized they needed Jews from other places of the world,
including the Arab world.
So look at the case, for example, of Morocco, King Hassan, the second was facing internal
conflict.
He was worried about a military coup within his country.
He made a deal with the Mossad for intelligence and weapons and training.
And in exchange, he would transfer the Jewish population in Morocco over to Israel.
And this in fact happened.
There's a New York times obituary that talks about this when King Hassan, the second died.
In fact, there was once an Arab league meeting that took place in Morocco and King Hassan
bugged the room for the Mossad, which helped them by the way, win the six day war.
Another story, for example, in Iraq, where the Mossad, a synagogue in Iraq, in order to
drive fear in the Iraqi Jewish community, in order for them to migrate to Israel.
And this is settled history.
The Israeli historian Avi Shlaim writes about this and the Mossad agents who are involved
in this, confess to it and boast about what they did by doing that to that synagogue.
In Yemen, the Emir of Yemen was paid a handsome sum of money by Israel in order to forcibly
transfer the Yemeni Jews to Israel.
And those Yemeni Jews had been there for thousands of years, maybe since the Babylonian expulsion.
Maybe 3000 years they were there in Yemen.
They were forcibly taken out of their homes and transferred to Israel because of a monetary
transaction between the Emir of Yemen and between Israel.
So as you can see, it is a little bit of a complex scenario.
Now, there were riots that happened against the Jews, places like Algeria and so on.
One of the points that I have to raise here is that the initial contention is that Islam
is at fault.
But all the world leaders at that time in the Arab world were Arab nationalists.
There were movements of secular organizations that were not motivated by Islam.
And finally, I'll say, if the Arab Jews wanted to go back to their land, wanted to go back
to their homes, wanted restitution, I would support them 100% in this.
What happened to them by and large was unjust and an injustice that happens to them is not
justification for injustice happening against the Palestinians.
What is the fault of the Palestinians if the Iraqis did something or the Egyptians did
something, the Syrians did something or the Yemenis did something?
What is the Palestinian fault in that?
Absolutely nothing.
And so to try to justify the ethnic cleansing and the extermination of the Palestinians because
of what happened to Jews in other Arab countries is nonsensical, frankly, ridiculous.